MUKHAMEDSALOVA **AIYA**

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | eaya94@gmail.com | 60-12-8832162

Creative Front-End Developer

Innovative and creative web developer with in excess of 3 years extensive experience in frontline development and testing of web-based applications. My strong background includes front-end development using HTML5, CSS3, SAAS/SCSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap – in addition to knowledge of version control systems such as SVN and Git, and a thorough understanding of object-oriented programming and design patterns. In my previous roles, I have worked closely with internal Product & Marketing Teams, and external agencies when required, to deliver innovative features across all digital touchpoints, and produce concepts into fully-functional user-validated product, through the use of our CMS (HubSpot, in the most recent example).

Experience

Front-End Developer (Nov 2017 - Present)

Seek Asia Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Solid background about HTML and CSS from image to code
- Having experience in Java Script and jQuery library
- Solid background about HTML and CSS from image to code
- Having experience in Java Script and jQuery library
- Understanding of ReactJS, Redux, AWS (CloudFormation, EC2, DynamoDB and etc), CI/CD, Unit Test (Jest), Docker
- Strong background of HubSpot (HubDB, HubL & EDM technical development) and OptinMonster
- Having Experience in PHP and related CMS (WordPress, Drupal and etc)
- Great understanding of Sketch App, Adobe Experience Design and Adobe Photoshop
- Expert of using Responsive Frameworks (Bootstrap, Materlizecss)
- Proficient understanding of code versioning tools such as Git and SVN
- Good Experience to work with Axure on mock ups and prototypes

Front-End Developer (Dec 2016 - Sept)

Trusted Company Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Solid background about HTML and CSS from image to code
- Great experience in SQL and understanding of Data Base structures
- Good understanding of ¡Query library
- Having Experience in PHP and related CMS (WordPress, Drupal and etc)
- Great understanding of Sketch App, Adobe Experience Design and Adobe Photoshop
- Expert of using Responsive Frameworks (Bootstrap, Materlizecss)
- Great experience with Play Framework
- Solid experience to work in a team with great team work
- Proficient understanding of code versioning tools, such as (Git)

- Good proficiency with JavaScript development, such as MVC, Unit Testing, UI testing and JavaScript documentation
- Understanding of Template rendering (e.g. Handlebars)
- Understanding of SEO

Intern Front-End Developer (Aug 2016 - Nov 2016)

Trusted Company Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Intern Front-End Developer (Jan 2016 - March 2016)

Mass Media Taldykorgan, Kazakhstan

Education

Bachelor of Information Communication Technology

Swinburne University of Technology (Australian University, Sarawak Campus) Sarawak, Malaysia

Awards and Achievements

TADHack Global Local Category – 2nd prize TADHack Local Category (Data Analytics)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Entrance Scholarship (2013 – 2014)

Swinburne University of Technology Sarawak, Malaysia

1st place International Olympiad in Geography

Geoolympaid Paphos, Cyprus

Languages

Excellent English, Russian and Kazakh

Hobbies

Reading Books | Travel | Painting | Dancing | Horseback riding | Skiing | Hiking

References are available upon request